

Mobile:

Mobile: <u>+385958283103</u>

M Email:

matej.jelusic@artapel.hr

Year of Birth: 1995.

Country: Croatia

Web: <u>artapel.hr</u>

Matej Jelušić

Senior Java Engineer

Well-rounded Senior Java engineer focused on Spring Boot. Proficient in a significant portion of the development lifecycle, including the scope of containerization, databases, database & code versioning, and CI/CD. Experienced in working with diverse remote teams, as well as mentoring less experienced co-workers

EXPERIENCE

Dec 2023 - Oct 2023

Senior Java Engineer @ HOBACA, remote, short term contract

- Tech stack: Java (17), Spring Boot 3, flyway migration scripts,
 Docker
- Worked for a startup client in the EV automotive industry
- Worked on the integration of the in-house fleet management & charging point management system with the eRoaming platform
- Acted as the sole developer responsible for managing product development and direct communication with stakeholders
- Collaboration with in-house development team for integration needs with eRoaming (Hubject platform)

Mar 2023 - Dec 2023

NodeJS Developer @ Belmond, remote, short term contract

- Tech stack: NodeJS (Express), Jest, BigQuery, WebSocket
- Worked on a microservice responsible for syncing 2 different enterprise HR software a conglomerate and one ifs branches
- The service solved the challenge of transitioning HR software at Belmond and ensuring interoperability between the systems
- Coordinated with project management at Belmond

Jul 2022 - Dec 2022

Full-Stack Developer @ HRAIS (Croatian Government Customs Office), remote, short term contract

Tech stack: Java (11), Thymeleaf, SoapUI

- Worked on a government project for the automation of import
- customs
 The project was a thorough API documentation requirement which then needed to be implemented on the backend and
- Worked on a project with a fixed end date (1.1.2023. before the Euro was introduced as the official currency of Croatia)

Jul 2022 - Dec 2023

External Consultant @ Protel hotelsoftware GmbH, remote

- Mentored new hires for the Protel dev team
- Delegated tasks to other engineers

frontend

- Contributed to tech support resolution with deep system insight
- Held lessons and solution reviews for junior dev members
- Contributed to regular system maintenance and check-ups

Mar 2021 - Jul 2022

Java Software Engineer @ Protel hotelsoftware GmbH, remote

- Tech stack: Java(11), Spring Boot, AWS (DataSync, EFS, S3, IAM, CloudWatch, etc.)
- Worked on transferring a lot of the previously learned concepts and practices to the provisioned cloud (AWS) instead of inhouse
- Worked as part of an international team

Jan 2020 - Mar 2021

Java Software Engineer @ INFOBIP, Zagreb - Croatia

- Tech stack: Java (8), Spring Boot, Microservices, Load Balancers,
 API Gateways, Prometheus/Grafana monitoring
- Worked in a large corporate development environment
- Worked within an in-house microservice architecture paradigm that spans the whole software offering of Infobip
- Worked on 2 critical microservices that are the lifeblood of the rest of the microservice network, Account Management System & Security Center
- Worked in a SCRUM project management setting with biweekly sprints with SCRUM poker for task estimation
- Dealt with the challenges of developing and maintaining a system that must have a perfect uptime and availability
- This experience was a big lesson for personal accountability and on how to structure, and monitor a system that is critical

Mar 2019 - Dec 2019

Java Developer @ SENLA Adriatic, Zagreb - Croatia

• Tech stack: Java (8), Spring Boot, Zuul, Eureka, Spring Cloud

Config Server, Docker, Fabric8, Swagger, Hystrix Circuit Breaker, PostgreSQL, jQuery, Microservices, Docker, GitLab CI/CD

- First project on which a microservice architecture was encountered
- Advanced my understanding of microservice architecture by implementing a microservice environment using Netflix technologies, including Eureka, Zuul, Hystrix Circuit Breaker and Spring Cloud Config Server
- Tackled on challenging service discovery through Eureka and complete setup of the project
- Project didn't go past the PoC stage during tenure
- Mentored under future CTO of another development agency

Jul 2017 - Mar 2019

Java Developer @ Verso Altima Group, Zagreb - Croatia

- Tech stack: Java (8), Spring Boot, Liquibase, H2, PostgreSQL, JavaScript (Vue), Kotlin, LDAP Api, Thymeleaf
- Worked within an internal development team for an HR administration tool
- Worked in a Kanban project context with daily stand-ups
- Implemented new features as per HR department requests for their 360 Degree Survey
- Experienced a technology playground with a real use-case project along with senior engineer mentoring within the company

EDUCATION

2017 - 2020 Master of Computer Engineering (MAG. ING. COMP)

Faculty of Electrical Engineering & Computing, Zagreb, Croatia

2013 - 2017Bachelor (baccalaureus) of Computer Engineering (BACC. ING.

COMP)

Faculty of Electrical Engineering & Computing, Zagreb, Croatia

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming language Java, JavaScript, Kotlin
- Framework Spring Boot, NodeJS, Vue, Angular
- Other technologies AWS, Gitlab CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes,
- Documentation, technical specifications & requirements

- Cloud computing
- Microservice architecture

SOFT SKILLS

- Mentoring and leadership: Mentored junior developers and students, helping them with technical challenges and providing guidance through code reviews and pair programming sessions.
- Communication and collaboration: Frequently led discussions to argue and justify ideas in team meetings, ensuring all stakeholders understood the proposed solutions and initiatives
- Initiative and ownership:
 - Initiated and led an effort to increase test coverage of a microservice from 0% to over 97%, designing and implementing a comprehensive testing architecture
 - o Led the complete integration of an EV platform with the eRoaming system

PRIVATE PROJECTS

- https://gitlab.com/matej.jelusic/kubernetes-master-thesis
- https://gitlab.com/matej.jelusic/igp-test
- https://gitlab.com/matejjj18/object-tracking-camshift
- https://gitlab.com/matej.jelusic/movies-recommender